Previously on Gotham...
Shall we begin?
I am not Bruce,
and I won't let you tell Alfred.
How you gonna stop...
I'd like to introduce our newest member,
James Gordon.
Welcome to the Court of Owls.
- Are you okay?
- I just remembered.
There's someone I need to kill.
This virus isn't a disease.
It's the best thing that's
ever happened to me.
I don't need a cure.
I will purge Gotham,
and the innocents will thank me!
Their savior!
Their executioner.
Guilty. Guilty.
What's this I see?
Captain Barnes being escorted
away by the orderlies.
Who is this new player
that enters the fray?
And with that, it was over.
Leaving me to wonder
what mysterious forces are at
play in the middle of the night.
Captain Barnes.
At last we meet.
Who are you?
Let's just say I'm a fan.
What do you want?
The same thing you do,
for Gotham to be judged
and the guilty punished.
Well, then release me
and I'll do just that.
Unfortunately...
we're looking to pass sentence
on a much larger scale.
And to do that we need
what's inside of you.
The virus.
Precisely. But don't worry.
I'll make sure he doesn't drain you...
completely.
Hello, Captain.
Strange.
I'm sorry, Captain.
This might sting.
Hey, Lee.
What's this?
My final report on Frank Gordon.
Cause of death...
homicide.
I thought Jim's uncle killed himself.
Did you?
Look, I know you're upset.
After everything you've been through...
D-Don't. Don't you dare do that.
This is not about Mario.
Then what's it about?
Why are, why are you here?
What do you want me to do?
Harvey, you are acting captain.
I want you to open an investigation
into the murder of Frank Gordon,
and I think Jim should be questioned.
You're accusing Jim of
killing his own uncle?
Why would he do that?
I don't know,
but I know that he is involved somehow,
maybe not in his death, but
maybe in covering it up,
making it look like a suicide.
And I want to know who else is involved.
Are you implying I'm involved as well?
Tell me I'm wrong, Harvey.
Tell me there's nothing else going on.
Look me in the eyes and tell me I'm crazy.
You're not crazy, Lee.
You're hurt.
And there's nothing going on.
We used to be friends, Harvey.
I know you're covering for him.
I don't know what he's involved in,
but I'm gonna find out.
The ruling council has decided
to suspend all Court activity
in order to focus our attention
on the preparations at hand.
Gotham's judgment is imminent.
To that end,
any members who have not
submitted their list for
review and approval
should do so today.
We are adjourned.
Excuse me?
Yeah?
I'm looking for a friend of mine.
Knock yourself out.
Her name's Selina.
Selina Kyle.
She knew Barbara Kean.
She used to hang out here.
I think.
You think?
You don't sound real close.
Oh, no, we were... kind of,
but she was always really bossy, you know?
And then we got into this fight.
I was gone for awhile and...
Yeah, I don't care.
Try Gotham General.
Did something happen to her?
I heard she fell out of a window
and is in pretty bad shape.
What are you doing in here?
I was supposed to put down
my list of names, but...
nobody told me what for.
Loved ones are to be spared
from the coming judgment.
Thank you.
No.
It can't be.
I'm sorry, this ward is restricted.
What happened to her?
No idea.
Police found her on the street.
Looks like she fell.
Fell?
That's impossible.
Is she gonna be all right?
No.
What do you mean, "No"?
Tell me she's gonna be all right.
- She's gonna be all right.
- No.
You're just saying that because I...
...just...
...tell me the truth.
We've tried everything.
All we can do now is make her comfortable.
Leave us and don't come back.
Don't listen to them, Selina.
They don't know what I know.
They can't do what I can do.
I will heal you.
I promise.
Isn't it enough, you holding
me against my will?
Must you also hover while I work?
I'd think you would prefer this
to playing nursemaid to Fish Mooney.
I was able to save Fish Mooney
despite the fact that she
had one foot in the grave.
I took it as a personal challenge.
Grandstanding doesn't suit you.
Were you able to accomplish what we asked?
See for yourself.
Hello?
What do you want from me?
Someone tell me what's going on.
Previously, the Alice Tetch
virus could only be transmitted
through direct contact with her blood.
What is that?
Someone please help!
We've done it.
You've weaponized the virus.
Pick it up.
No.
You win,
and you go free.
Pick up the stick,
and defeat this man.
You're lying.
This is just another way
of manipulating me.
Pick it up.
Prove me wrong.
All that pain and anger...
you think it's strength.
It's not.
You think can harness it... you can't.
You think it's part of you,
but it doesn't have to be.
Do you know why you were
so easily defeated?
No.
Your rage, Bruce.
It blinds you.
You seek to control it,
and yet it controls you
and has ever since that night.
Rage and pain are two
sides of the same coin.
I can release you from
the pain of that night.
And when I do,
nothing will be able to stop you.
Listen, Jim,
we got a hit on the prints
you lifted off the mask.
Kathryn's last name is Monroe.
She's from one of
Gotham's oldest families.
Her address is 450 clinton Ave...
Nice work, Harvey.
Kathryn seems to be the only one
who knows what the weapon is.
So what's the plan?
Break in, see what I can find out.
What do you think,
she's keeping it on her fireplace mantel?
I searched the Court chambers.
She isn't taking any chances
with the rank and file
knowing what the weapon is.
If there is something to find,
it'll be at her house.
That's a big risk.
You get caught, ball game over.
I don't have a choice.
Listen, Jim, about your uncle...
Lee came into my office wanting to
open an investigation into his death.
She asked me point blank
what you were doing.
What'd you say?
Nothing.
I lied.
Jim,
she seemed like she was
in a pretty dark place.
Anything else?
Yeah. Not to add on,
but I got a call from a buddy
of mine at Arkham last night.
Barnes was transferred.
Transferred? To where?
We don't know.
I got Alvarez looking into it.
But don't worry, we will find him.
Thanks, Harvey.
Jim, be careful.
Oswald.
Hello, Jim.
Guess I shouldn't be surprised
you're still alive.
Yes, I am quite hard to kill.
I take it this isn't a social call.
I'm looking for Ed.
We have some unfinished business.
And it turns out
you are the last one who saw him.
Yeah, before he escaped police custody.
"Escaped"?
From the great Detective Gordon?
I think not.
Ed went on television
demanding information
about a group that runs Gotham.
A group called the "Court."
And you called him and said
you had that information.
A ruse to get him to the GCPD.
Perhaps.
But then you arrest him,
and, voilà, he disappears.
Sorry, "escapes custody."
Can you see how I might think
you may have handed Ed off to this
all-powerful group for some reason?
For your own sake, Oswald,
drop it.
I knew it.
You don't know anything.
Trust me, let it go.
Sorry, no can do.
I assume the Court doesn't like publicity,
hence Ed's sudden disappearance
after his television debut.
But that is exactly what
they're going to get.
Unless they deal with me in a
civilized and professional manner.
I'm sure you wouldn't mind
facilitating something on my behalf.
My number is the only one in here.
I will expect a call
by the end of the day.
Why do I get the sense
I'm being threatened?
This is a favor, Jim.
After all, we're old friends.
Right?
Thomas?
Yes, ma'am.
Kathryn.
Detective Gordon, what
is the meaning of this?
Who let you in here?
Oswald Cobblepot is alive
and back in Gotham.
He paid me a visit this morning.
He knows Nygma's disappearance
has something to do with the Court.
Is that all?
I'm tired of being kept in the dark.
I want a seat at the table.
How ambitious.
You asked me to be on the Court.
Now, I have done everything you've asked.
I think I've proved my commitment.
I want to know what's going on.
I want to know what the judgment entails.
And if you don't like what you hear?
Try me.
Gotham is sick.
Crime and violence are so common
the people have become numb to it.
To heal the city,
we have to force them to take notice.
Force them how?
By showing the people of
Gotham their darkest selves.
I'll consider your request.
Now leave my house at once.
It's Harvey. Leave a message.
Harvey, I know what the weapon is.
I know how they're gonna
pass judgment on Gotham.
The weapon is the Alice Tetch virus?
Kathryn said the weapon would
"show Gotham its darkest self."
Alice Tetch was in Indian Hill for years.
They would have known about her.
It's the virus. I'm sure of it.
Is that even possible?
Well, that's why you're here, Lucius.
I'm sorry to throw you into the
deep end of the pool like this,
but I need to know what we're up against.
You mean beyond a secret society
that controls all of Gotham.
Well, if they could isolate the virus
they could transform it into
any number of compounds
that could be released on a
large scale into the city.
All they'd need is a sample of her blood.
Well, they ain't getting
it from the source.
After Mario broke into the hematology lab,
they destroyed the rest of Alice's blood.
I mean, where do they get a sample?
They don't need a sample of Alice's blood,
just a sample of the virus.
The virus that she passed along
to the people she infected.
Barnes.
Exactly.
Barnes wasn't transferred out of Arkham,
Kathryn kidnapped him.
So... if we can find out
where he was taken,
we can stop this.
And how do we go about doing that?
I found this in Kathryn's study.
- Any idea what lab it belongs to?
- No.
But when I was running the Wayne
Enterprises R&D division,
we only had a half dozen off-site labs.
Barnes isn't exactly the kind
of guy who's gonna blend in.
It'd have to be somewhere isolated,
and small enough for them to control.
I think I know where they took him.
Just put them down wherever there's space,
and then go back to where I found you.
Yes, ma'am.
Selina,
I would like to introduce
you to nepeta Cataria.
Or, rather, a very specialized
strain of a plant
that I've been cultivating.
This guy is a "break in case
of emergency" type of deal.
You've always been there for me.
Even when I screwed things up.
Which was most of the time.
Just breathe deep,
and I'll be here when you wake up.
Just wake up, okay?
Are we going back to the alley
where my parents were murdered?
No.
There's another memory
I want to start with.
The first time you felt the rage
after your parents' death...
Do you remember?
Yes.
The rage from that day continues
to burn inside of you,
feeding on your pain,
blinding you from everything else,
and, if left unchecked,
will one day consume you.
We need to remove it before that happens.
You want me to give up
my memory of that day?
No. The events themselves will remain.
I'm only talking about releasing you
from the destructive emotions
connected with them.
And if I don't want to be released?
You have chosen your prison, Bruce.
I'm offering you a way out.
Why?
You said I was to become
the protector of Gotham.
Why me?
Because you need each other.
Gotham needs a protector,
and you need a purpose.
I'm only trying to show you the way.
But it has to be...
...your choice.
Do you know where you are?
My parents' wake.
Yes.
You were surrounded by friends and family,
and yet...
I felt alone.
This was the first time I truly processed
that my parents were gone.
The first time I thought
of myself as an orphan.
Is that why you left?
No.
Then why did you?
I heard what they were saying.
He witnessed the whole thing.
He must have been terrified.
Devastated.
Traumatized.
My parents were dead, but all
anybody was talking about was me.
How concerned they were about me.
My parents had been murdered.
Gunned down and left for
dead and nobody seemed...
Angry.
Yes.
And so you left.
I hid in my parents' room.
My father was supposed to be
buried in a pair of cufflinks
that I'd bought him for his
birthday the year before.
He always said they were his favorite.
But when it came time to give them up...
...I couldn't let them go.
It's time to let them go.
There.
You can lock it away, and once you do,
you'll be free of the
power it holds over you.
I've been waiting a long
time for this, Bruce.
Together,
we will make Gotham pay.
No guards.
No security.
I don't like it, either.
I guess we know where the guards went.
Hello?
GCPD.
Freeze.
The police, thank God.
Keep your hands where we can see them!
I didn't want to kill these people, I-I...
I just lost control.
On the ground, now.
Now!
I'm the good guy here.
Oh, you're just like them.
You're out to get me.
What have you done with the virus?
Who has it?
A woman, named Kathryn.
Where is she? Where's she taken it?
I don't know.
As I told you, I was brought
here against my will.
I know nothing of their other plans.
Hugo Strange, you're under arrest
for attempts to weaponize a viral...
hell, you know why.
Oh, you don't want to do that.
The delivery mechanism
that they plan to use
to release the virus
just recently arrived.
The shipment that came into dock 9C.
Yes.
It still needs to be tested,
which means that you
still have enough time
to keep them from unleashing it citywide.
But, of course,
if they discover that their
lab has been compromised...
He's right, they might
unleash it right away.
We can't take him in
or the Court will know we're onto them.
Are you crazy? What if
he's yanking our chain?
What stops him from picking up the phone
and calling the owl brigade the
second we walk out that door?
My research.
And a vial of my virus compound
which I secreted away,
unbeknownst to my captors.
A token of goodwill,
which I hope will be remembered
when the time comes.
Goodwill?
You're playing both sides.
You help us take down the Court and what?
We cut you a deal?
But we fail,
and you appear to be loyal
to the Court, is that it?
You logical bastard.
Don't worry about the mess.
We have our poor test
subject to blame for that.
Good luck, detectives.
Get Lucius the virus
compound and the research.
See if he can find anyone we can trust
to start working on the cure.
Where you going?
I gotta find out where
Kathryn's testing the bomb.
Kathryn?
I've thought about what you said.
You have done what we've asked.
Maybe it is time to take the next step.
Meet me at 331 Smith Place.
Can't give me any more than that?
You said you didn't want
to be kept in the dark.
Let's see if you're worthy of the light.
Is that all you have?
I thought you wanted to leave this place.
That's it!
That's it.
Yes.
See what you can accomplish
once you remove destructive emotions?
Tell me,
how did you feel when you
were fighting this time?
I felt...
...nothing.
I beat him.
Does that mean I can leave?
Is that what you want?
The pain to go away?
I can take it away, Bruce.
I can take it away and
you can return to Gotham
with a power you never thought possible.
It's your choice.
Get up.
We're not done.
James.
Glad you could make it.
Not sure I had a choice.
I'm afraid I'm going to have to ask
you for your gun and your phone.
Nice party.
The daughters of Gotham.
Socialites who believe they
hold the power in this city,
when really what they really
are is window dressing.
My family was one of the first in Gotham.
We've been on the Court
since its founding,
making the difficult decisions
to ensure its long-term survival.
Which is why I've brought you here.
Interesting centerpiece.
It's an aerosol dispersal bomb.
Dispersal bomb for what?
For the Alice Tetch virus.
So that's what you meant by
showing Gotham its darkest self.
Precisely.
Infecting 200 people won't change anything.
- True.
But the virus compound
only lives in aerated form
for a matter of minutes,
so, in a closed space like the room below,
it will be contained to our guests.
But in an open space,
the radius of infection is a half mile.
This is merely a test.
Place it in the middle of the room.
Don't worry, you'll be safe up here.
I need to trust
that you're ready to make
the difficult decisions
when the time comes.
That's why I'm here.
Good.
Because if it's not,
if you try to stop the bomb
or interfere in any way,
Talon has instructions to
execute you on the spot.
Talon, right?
I'm assuming that's a nickname.
Right.
Wouldn't want to miss out
on the sounds of 200 people
tearing each other's throats out.
The device is in place.
Hello, Jim.
I was beginning to think I
wasn't going to hear from you.
I met you the other night, didn't I?
When you took Nygma?
- Jim?
- I keep wondering...
...what it is the Court is
planning to do with him.
Stop talking.
This used to be a bank, right?
First Bank of Gotham?
I just hope it can withstand
whatever the bomb's going to do to it.
It sounds like we don't have much time.
Shut up.
Sure.
Where's Jim?
He's not responding to my calls.
I'm heading into the bullpen
to see if anyone's heard from him.
What's going on?
Hey, Lee.
Are you helping Jim?
Bullock, I get.
But has Jim also pulled
you into his madness?
- It's not madness, Lee.
- Then what is it?
How many people does he have to kill
before you all see what I see?
You got it wrong.
Jim's trying to make sure
that what happened to Mario
never happens to anyone again.
What are you talking about?
Lucius.
Please, just tell me what's going on.
I can't.
I'm sorry, Lee.
You're just like everybody else here.
Screw it.
Duck.
Everyone out!
Now!
Took you long enough.
I need to get these people out of here.
And I need to talk to the Court.
Have them turn over Ed. Remember?
There is a bomb down there
with a weaponized version
of the Alice Tetch virus.
If you want to be here when
it goes off, be my guest.
What about our deal?
You just torched their assassin.
My guess is, they'll be in touch.
Mommy! Mom!
Mommy!
Where's my daughter? Where's my daughter?!
Yes, sir.
Hello, Kathryn.
My apologies for the time.
Not at all.
How are things progressing
with Bruce Wayne?
Excellent.
He believes in the
destiny I have promised,
in a life free from the pain of his past.
The boy and I will be leaving tonight.
I trust everything will be in
place by the time we arrive.
Of course.
Why haven't they made contact?
And where the hell is Ivy
and the human popsicle?
Hello?
Are you listening to me?
You're awake.
Selina!
Are you okay?
Say something so that I know you're okay.
Why does my room smell like
a giant bag of potpourri?
You're back.
Oh, I can't believe it.
Oh, wait.
What are you doing?
You just got out of a coma.
You need to rest.
This can't wait.
What are you talking about?
Where are you going?
To Wayne Manor.
To kill someone.
What are you doing?
What does it look like I'm doing?
I'm leaving.
Well, actually, I'm resigning,
and then I'm leaving.
Don't. You belong here.
I thought I did.
Then you infected this place
and everyone around you.
I'm done.
I am done with you, with the GCPD...
With Gotham.
What are you talking about?
You've taken everything away from me.
Everything.
There's nothing left.
And for what?
I would ask you for the truth,
but I honestly don't even think
you know what that is anymore.
You want the truth?
Fine.
I killed Mario.
I'm done apologizing for it.
He was gonna kill you.
- No.
- I saw the knife.
I saw the knife and I pulled the trigger.
And I would do it again.
- He was infected.
- Yes.
Because Jervis Tetch
wanted to punish you. You!
Not Mario. Mario didn't
deserve what happened to him.
You want to blame me for
Mario's death, fine!
You want to walk out that door and
never come back, I can't stop you.
But it will not help.
Believe me.
The other day, you asked
me at Mario's grave
how I could walk away.
Move on.
I guess you know how.
My name is Oswald Cobblepot.
You cannot do this to me.
I demand to speak to the person in charge!
Oswald.
You're alive?
I want to apologize for
my curt behavior earlier.
We both want the same thing for Gotham.
Judgment.
But I have just discovered
someone I thought was loyal
has been deceiving me from the start.
Detective James Gordon
now threatens to undo what we both seek.
I need you to kill him
before he can do that.
Jim Gordon is guilty.
And I will be his executioner.
www.tvsubtitles.net